Han... Han Shuo!
韓 韓爍
Listen to me! This is the moment
現在這個時候 我告訴你
to test
就是 就是看
the hero's character.
男主人品的時候
You've got to withstand the test!
你一定要經得住考驗啊
Han Shuo!
韓爍
Han Shuo! Wake up!
韓爍 醒醒
The smell of the aphrodisiac incense will kill you if you hold your desire.
合歡香憋久了是會死人的
You are my rightful wife,
你我是明媒正娶的夫妻
but we haven't slept together.
卻遲遲沒有圓房
It makes sense though.
也是
We didn't do the wedding parade,
我們沒有遊街
didn't offer sacrifice to Heaven,
沒有祭天
didn't even hold a formal ceremony.
也沒有拜堂
If I can get back to Huayuan alive,
我若有命回花垣
I promise I'll make it up to you!
一定還你
It's bad karma,
算我倒黴
since I took you away to marry me that day.
誰讓那天是我搶的親
I don't want you to die.
我不想你死
I swear to God
我韓爍對天起誓
that I won't ever betray you,
此生我定不負你
or I'll die a violent death...
否則萬箭穿心
Young Master, I'm here to save you!
少君 我來救你了
There you go!
我去
Fortunately, I got here in time!
幸虧我來得及時啊
Young Master,
少君
Zi Rui came to me in a hurry
剛才梓銳匆匆忙忙找到我
and told me that Her Highness was in danger.
說少城主有難
Su Ziying also came to me for help.
蘇子嬰也過來拉我
Luckily, I found a basin of cold water in the nick of time
幸虧我關鍵時刻尋得一盆涼水
and broke in with all my strength.
憑著蠻力闖了進去
Otherwise...
不然的話
Otherwise, what?
不然怎樣
I... I just realized I did something wrong!
我 我才反應過來
Young Master,
少君
please give me another chance to fix my mistakes!
給屬下一個將功補過的機會吧
Do you know how many times you've said it
自從來到花垣城
since we came to Huayuan City?
你知道這話你說了多少遍嗎
Bai Ji,
白芨
do you want to return to Xuanhu City?
你想回玄虎城嗎
No, I don't.
不想
We almost consummated our relationship.
這差一點就生米煮成熟飯
But why do I feel a little sorry that we didn't?
可是我為什麼覺得有點可惜呢
I even want to kill Bai Ji for interrupting us.
甚至還想打死白芨
When we were in the storage room,
在雜貨間的時候
why didn't I push him away?
我為什麼也沒想推開他
No way! No way!
不可能 不可能
How could I fall in love with Han Shuo?
我怎麼可能會喜歡韓爍呢
Xiaoqian, calm yourself!
小千 你要冷靜
Although you've never been in love
雖然你二十多年來
for the past 20-plus years,
都沒有談過戀愛
Han Shuo is just a fictitious figure.
可 可韓爍他就是個紙片人
You...
你
You can't be desperate like this!
你也不能這麼飢不擇食
He has his own mission in this story,
他有他的故事任務
and you...
你
you are from a totally different world.
你們倆根本就不是一個世界的人
Exactly!
對
And he's not that special.
他也就還好啊
He's just a little handsome,
就只不過是 有一點帥
a little manly,
霸氣了一點
well versed in both literature and martial arts.
文武雙全
And,
而且
he's good at flirting!
還會撩妹
But people say
可是別人不是說
that your heart will beat faster
喜歡一個人的時候
when you see someone you love.
見到他都會心跳加速嗎
I don't think my heart beats faster
可是我見到韓爍
when I see Han Shuo.
也沒有心跳加速
Chen Qianqian.
陳芊芊
I was
剛才
being abrupt earlier.
是我唐突了
No big deal!
這算什麼事啊
We just kissed and touched each other a little bit.
剛才不就親了兩下 摸了兩下嗎
What? You want me to be responsible for you?
怎麼 想要我對你負責
Do you want me to be responsible for you?
那你需不需要我對你負責
Not necessary!
不需要
I don't even care.
壓根沒放在心上
I was actually worried
我倒是還擔心韓少君
if your vulnerable heart could take it.
會不會心裡有後遺症呢
What was I talking about?!
我在說什麼
Don't worry.
放心
I'll be fine.
我一切都好
I won't ruin the rest of your life.
不會遺禍你後半生幸福的
Let me see if you got hurt.
我看看有沒有傷到
What's that sound?
什麼聲音
I once blamed Heaven
我曾抱怨上蒼
for having me suffer from heart disease.
讓我身患心疾
Yet you stole the Dragon Bone and cured me.
是你盜取龍骨 救治了我
If you were born in Xuanhu City,
若你生在玄虎城
I'd absolutely send an eight-carrier sedan to marry you,
我必定八抬大轎娶你
abide by the principle of the "Three Letters and Six Etiquettes".
三書六禮
I'd use swan goose to deliver the letters,
鴻雁為信
and spend
一生
the rest of my life
一世
with you.
一雙人
No one will ever get in the way of us.
你我之間再沒有別人
But in Huayuan City,
可在花垣城
women aren't serious about love, I guess.
大概女子就是薄情吧
Do you understand
我的心意
my heart now?
你現在明白了吧
Can't believe Han Shuo loves me?!
韓爍居然喜歡我
No wonder he said
怪不得他說
that he didn't want me to put him together with Chuchu.
不願我將他與楚楚湊到一塊呢
Turns out he's in love with me!
原來他喜歡上我了
But he can't be in love with me!
他不能喜歡我呀
So strange!
奇怪
Why it feels like there are butterflies
為什麼心裡有一頭小鹿在
in my stomach?
撞啊 撞啊 撞啊
Your Highness!
少城主
What happened exactly?
到底發生了什麼事
The Crown Princess and Young Master Han
少城主與韓少君
were locked in a storage room
被鎖在雜貨間
and exposed to aphrodisiac incense.
還中了合歡香
Aphrodisiac incense?
合歡香
That was an accident!
意外意外
I happened to go to the storage room to find something,
這是我剛好去雜貨間找東西
and bumped into Young Master Han,
誰知道碰到了中了合歡香的
who was exposed to aphrodisiac incense.
韓少君
I thought this thing was very weird.
小人想著此事蹊蹺
The pageboy of the inn must have had something to do with it.
定與客棧小廝有關
So I wanted to ask him,
想尋他前來問話
but I couldn't find him anywhere.
卻 怎麼也找不著人了
I guess
小人猜想
he must have fled
那小廝怕是行跡敗露
for fear of punishment.
畏罪潛逃了
Do you have evidence
你有什麼證據證明
to prove that he did it?
這事是他乾的
It's just my suspicion.
小人也只是猜測
If he were innocent,
若小廝是無辜的
why would he escape?
為何 他就心虛逃走了呢
He must have been involved.
此人肯定脫不了干係
But in this case,
但這樣一來
we'll have no way to find out who's the mastermind.
就不知道是誰在背後指使了
I'm useless!
都是小人沒用
I couldn't catch that pageboy
抓不到小廝
to find out who was behind it.
問不出幕後之人
I failed to serve Your Highness and Young Master well!
無法替三公主與韓少君分憂
I have let my master down!
小人 愧對我家公子的囑託
Obviously, it was...
明明就
Obviously, it was done by that pageboy himself.
明明就是那小廝一個人做的
There's nothing more to investigate.
有什麼好查的
It was all that pageboy's fault, wasn't it?
都怪那小廝 對吧
Yes, it was.
對的呢
Your Highness,
少城主
Su Ziying was clearly lying,
這蘇子嬰分明就是在狡辯
why didn't you call him out?
你為何不當場揭穿他呀
I have my reason to keep him.
這留著他自然有我的用處
That pageboy was able to escape secretly
這替蘇子嬰行事的小廝
after helping Su Ziying.
能夠神不知鬼不覺地捲包跑路
What does that tell you?
說明什麼
It shows that Su Ziying is very cautious
說明蘇子嬰這個人行事周全
and sly.
讓人抓不到馬腳
Young Master,
少君
why didn't you just kill that Su Ziying,
您為何不一刀宰了那蘇子嬰
in case he'll harm Her Highness again?
任由他蠱惑陷害少城主
I certainly have my reason to keep him.
留著他 自然有我的用意
He's good at lying.
他擅長顛倒黑白
It's easy to kill him,
殺他自然容易
but if the lies remain,
怕的是落下口實
Pei Heng may use them as excuses
讓裴恆借題發揮
to slander me in front of Qianqian.
在芊芊面前詆譭坑害我
Then let him bring it on!
那就讓他坑我好了
Why did Su Ziying
蘇子嬰做這麼多事情
do all those things?
無非是什麼
His purpose was to get me out of the way of Chuchu.
無非就是想讓我給楚楚讓路
Fine!
好
I'll make him satisfied!
那我就成全他
Why does Su Ziying try to harm Qianqian?
蘇子嬰針對芊芊能為什麼
Of course it's for the Crown Princess position.
自然是為了少城主之位
As long as I'm here,
有我在
I won't let anybody
誰也別想把她
take her down from that position.
從那個位子上拉下來
I just feel sorry for Pei Heng.
現在就是可憐裴恆
He's still kept in the dark
還被矇在鼓裡
and thinks
在他的心裡
that Su Ziying
蘇子嬰固然還是一個
is a loyal person.
忠心可靠的人呢
By then, we'll
到時候再將他
reveal his acts of harming Qianqian,
傷害芊芊的行徑戳破
and bring him to Pei Heng.
然後送到裴恆面前
Let's see how Pei Heng will deal with it.
我看裴恆如何自處
I will keep an eye on him.
屬下一定暗中盯梢
I won't miss any detail.
不放過任何一個細節
Very good!
甚好
So, let's keep everything normal.
所以 咱們就一切照舊
We'll play along and watch him at the same time.
配合為主 盯梢為輔
Don't let Su Ziying feel anything different.
讓蘇子嬰察覺不到一絲異樣
In that case,
既然如此
Your Highness, don't be angry
少城主 你就別生氣了
for Su Ziying anymore.
為個蘇子嬰
It's not worth it.
不值得
I'm not angry. I'm not.
不生氣 不生氣
No matter how annoying the role is,
這再討厭的角色
it was created by myself.
都是我自己寫的
I saw it coming. I'm not embarrassed.
自己氣自己 不丟人
Then why are you patting your chest?
那你還一直拍胸脯
I'm patting my chest
我拍胸脯是為了
to calm the butterflies
是為了讓我這個小鹿
in me.
不要再亂撞了
Your Highness,
少城主
the Second Princess asks you to play chess with her.
二郡主請您過去切磋切磋棋藝
Play chess?
棋藝
Why did you want to play chess with me all of a sudden?
二姐為何突然要約我下棋呀
I remember when we were little,
記得我們年幼時
we played gomoku all the time.
總是下五子棋
You could never win
我讓你八步
even when I let you take the first eight moves.
你也贏不了我
Right.
對
You always thought of me first.
二姐從小就讓著我
You still do nowadays.
現在也是如此
I've always given you whatever you wanted
你從小到大想要什麼
since we were little.
我都會讓給你
Over time,
讓著讓著
you've kinda got used to it.
你就成習慣了
If...
那
If I give you back
那要是我把原本
the thing that originally belonged to you,
就該屬於你的東西還給你
will you accept it?
你還會要嗎
The thing that originally belonged to me?
原本屬於我的
You are quite concerned about our city.
二姐心懷天下
You are more qualified
那自然是比我
to be the Crown Princess than me.
更勝任少城主之位了
But that's not
可我想要的
the only thing I want.
不止是這個
You mean...
二姐的意思是
You and Young Master Han were locked in the storage room today,
今日你和韓少君被鎖在雜貨間
and both of you were exposed to aphrodisiac incense.
還中了合歡香
Speaking of that, I'm so mad!
說到這事我就來氣
It's all that pageboy's fault that...
都怪那小廝
You are Han Shuo's wife.
你們不是夫妻嗎
If he wanted to harm you,
要害你們
why would he do something like that?
何必如此行事
I think the one he meant to lock in there
我看他真正想要鎖的
wasn't you.
不是你吧
Chuchu...
二姐
As far as I'm concerned,
我怎麼覺得
it was the same trick as the one you used
這和那日三妹害我掉進陷阱
when you lured me into a trap
引韓少君救我
and asked Han Shuo to save me.
有異曲同工之處呢
Feels like the tricks
這連環計
were done by the same person.
倒像是出自一人之手
Was it because last time it didn't work,
該不會是上次我和韓少君沒成
so you asked someone
三妹又想叫人
to poison me and Han Shuo with aphrodisiac incense.
給我和韓少君下合歡香
But that pageboy made a mistake
只是這中間辦差的小廝
in the process
出了點差錯
and locked you in there
把三妹自己
instead of me.
給鎖了進去
Not really.
不是不是
Chuchu, it's a misunderstanding.
二姐 這件事情真的是有誤會
Please don't misunderstand me.
我 你千萬不要誤會我
Please don't blame me.
你不要怪我
I don't blame you.
我不怪你
Instead, I need to thank you.
我還得謝謝你
Thank me?
謝我
This time,
這一次
I won't back down anymore.
我不會再讓著你了
If you don't want Han Shuo, I will.
你不要韓爍 我要
You want him? Well...
你要 這
I'm fond of Han Shuo.
我心悅於韓爍
You fell for him that fast?
這麼快就喜歡上了
What? Feel sad about losing him?
怎麼 捨不得了
No.
沒有
I'm just...
我只是
Actually, that makes it a lot easier.
如此就簡單多了
It's a good thing!
這是好事啊
You are supposed to fall in love with him.
二姐本該就喜歡他的
So you were saying
三妹的意思是
you'll let me have him?
會成全我
Don't worry, Chuchu. I'll take care of it.
二姐放心 都包在我身上
After getting back to Huayuan City,
回到花垣城
I'll figure out a way to divorce Han Shuo
我就想辦法跟韓爍和離
and give him back to you.
把韓爍還給你
Han Shuo
這韓爍
is still that Han Shuo.
還是以前的韓爍
I didn't touch him at all.
我一點都沒碰過
He's intact.
完璧
I won!
我贏了
Your Highness.
少城主
Why are you covering your chest again?
你怎麼又捂著胸口了呢
Where are my butterflies?
我小鹿呢
I don't feel fluttery anymore.
小鹿怎麼不蹦躂了呢
But you seem to be unhappy.
可是 我看起來你不太開心呀
How can I be happy about losing chess game?
輸了棋能開心嗎
I only lost a chess game,
不就輸了盤棋嗎
but how come
怎麼搞的
it feels like I've lost the whole world?
像輸了全世界一樣
We'll set out soon! Be careful
一會兒出發 一切小心
and follow my lead!
聽我指揮
Yes!
是
Young Master Han, I don't mean to offend you,
韓少君 不是小人逾越
but Her Highness doesn't allow me to get off.
是少城主不讓小人下車
Neither does she allow me to get off.
少城主也不讓我下車
Han Shuo, stop it!
韓爍 你別弄
Han Shuo!
韓爍
Han Shuo! What are you doing?
韓爍 你幹什麼
Put me down!
放我下去
From now on,
從今以後
I won't allow you to ride the carriage with other men!
不準跟別的男人坐一輛馬車
Han Shuo! Put me down!
韓爍 你把我放下去
Or I'll jump off myself!
要不然我跳下去了
I'm serious!
我真跳
Han Shuo,
韓爍
I do not like you.
我根本就不喜歡你
What did you say?
你說什麼
I said "I don't like you!"
我說我根本就不喜歡你
Didn't you hear me?
你聽不見嗎
I don't believe it.
我不信
You obviously have me in your heart.
你心裡明明有我
Why don't you admit it?
你為什麼不承認
Would you please stop being a narcissist?
我說你能不能別這麼自戀
I am Chen Qianqian, for God's sake!
我是誰 我陳芊芊
I've seen so many men in my life.
我見過的男子這麼多
I don't feel excited about you anymore.
我對你就是新鮮感
Don't think I can't live without you!
你以為我離不開你了
You were lying!
撒謊
See?
你看
You didn't even push me away!
你都不推開我
You were just bluffing!
你就是嘴硬
Anyway, I can't be with you.
反正我不能跟你在一起
Otherwise, it'll make a lot of trouble.
否則很多事情都會亂套的
I don't care.
我都不在乎
As long as I'm in your heart,
你只要心裡有我
there'll be no room for other guys.
就顧不上別人了
Whatever you think. Anyway,
你就這麼理解吧 反正
we are just like Huayuan City and Xuanhu City.
我跟你就像花垣城跟玄虎城
We are from two completely different worlds.
我跟你不是一個世界的人
I can't give up my world
我也沒有辦法 因為你
just for you.
放棄我的世界
And I can't
我也沒辦法
stay here all the time.
一直留在這兒
So will you be with me
那是不是隻要解決了
if the problem between Huayuan
花垣和玄虎的問題
and Xuanhu is solved?
你就跟我在一起
You'll never understand.
你永遠都不會明白的
Report!
報
Great victory achieved on Weimeng Mountain!
威猛山大捷
Your Majesty,
稟告城主
the bandits on Weimeng Mountain
威猛山流寇
have submitted to Her Highness' enlistment!
盡數被少城主招安
The bandits have been successfully suppressed!
少城主剿匪大捷
Good!
好
I knew that she could make it!
我就知道她能行
All the best to Her Highness!
賀少城主大喜
All the best to Your Majesty!
賀城主大喜
All the best to Huayuan City!
賀花垣城大喜
Your Majesty, now you can be relieved!
城主這次終於可以放心了
Su,
蘇兄
I'm new here,
我這人生地不熟的
hope I can have your support in the future.
以後還要靠你多照應啊
Meng, I'm flattered.
孟大哥說笑了
I'm just a servant.
我不過 是個下人
Be careful!
慢點啊
Gently move the cases.
那個箱子一定要輕拿輕放
Okay?
知道吧
It's such a huge yard!
這院子可真大
Meng Guo.
孟過
Let's give them a hand.
我們來幫個忙吧
Alright.
好
What are you doing?
幹嗎呢
Don't act confused.
嗯什麼嗯
The Crown Princess just gave an order.
少城主剛剛下令
From now on...
從今以後
...as the study is an important place...
書房重地
...in which is stored with a lot of confidential documents...
多有機密
...so the irrelevant people...
閒雜人等
...won't be allowed in!
免進
Meng,
孟大哥
here is   different from Weimeng Mountain.
這不是在威猛山寨
We have to follow the rules.
我們得講點規矩
Meng.
孟大哥
If you need any help, just ask me.
有什麼事 儘管找我
Let me take you to your room.
我領你去房間
Thank you, Su!
多謝蘇兄
Master, greetings to you!
見過公子
Has Qianqian got back to her mansion?
芊芊回府安頓下了
How is she doing?
她一切可好
Did you take good care of her
威猛山一行
on the Weimeng Mountain trip?
你可有照顧好她
What... What are you doing?
你 你這是做什麼
Master, I kept your words in mind
小人謹記公子的叮囑
and did my best to take care of the Third Princess.
盡心盡力地照料三公主
But Han Shuo
可韓爍
sowed discord between Her Highness and me.
卻挑撥小人與三公主的關係
And now, Her Highness suspects that I'm up to something
現在三公主懷疑小人身懷異心
and doesn't trust me anymore!
不肯再信任小人
That's just the way Han Shuo is!
韓爍此人一貫如此
Please rise.
你起來吧
But Han Shuo
可韓爍他
not only intercepted my letter to you,
不僅截斷小人與公子的信件
but also repeated put Her Highness
還在剿匪途中
in danger during the trip.
屢次置三公主於死地
What? Stand up and talk!
什麼 你站起來說
Han Shuo played up to the Second Princess all the time,
韓爍不僅處處討好二郡主
while he left the Third Princess in the inn alone.
還把三公主一人丟在客棧
As a result, she was taken by the bandit Meng Guo.
導致她被孟過賊人擒獲
When his scheme of harming Her Highness was exposed,
暗害三公主事敗後
Han Shuo
韓爍
used the aphrodisiac incense
還藉著合歡香
to try to take advantage of Her Highness!
妄圖輕薄三公主
Really?
竟有這種事
After Han Shuo's evil plan failed,
暗害三公主事敗後
Her Highness got confused about Han Shuo's intention,
是三公主被韓爍迷了心智
so she kept putting up with him,
才會對他一忍再忍
If Her Highness asks you to get me back,
如果 三公主讓您將小人收回
then...
那這個
Don't worry.
你放心
I'll persuade her
我會說服她
to let you stay in her mansion.
讓你繼續留在她府中
Qianqian is young and ignorant.
芊芊少不經事
You need to help her as much as you can.
你要多輔助她
Yes!
小人遵命
In fall she howls to let leaves fall;
解落三秋葉
In spring she hums to rouse flowers.
能開二月花
Across the sea she whirls waves miles tall;
過江千尺浪
Through bamboos she bends them with her power.
入竹萬竿斜
Let me repeat.
我再讀一遍
In fall she howls to let leaves fall...
解落三秋葉
How should I turn Han Shuo down
我到底要怎麼拒絕韓爍
to let him give up?
他才會放棄啊
I can't resist his gaze!
這種眼神 遭不住啊
Through bamboos she bends them with her power.
入竹萬竿斜
Next,
接下來
let's read "Mountain Life On An Autumn Evening" by Wang Wei.
我們讀王維的山居秋暝
After fresh rain in the empty mountains;
空山新雨後
the evening weather heralds autumn's arrival.
天氣晚來秋
The bright moon shines between the pines;
明月鬆間照
the clear spring water flows over the stones.
清泉石上流
Minister Pei,
裴司學
would you please stand here to teach today,
你今天就站在這兒上課吧
so that I can hear you more clearly?
這樣我能聽得更仔細一些
Sure.
也好
It's the best I can do under the circumstances.
非常時刻 出此下策
Sorry, Pei Heng.
對不起了裴恆
By the way, Minister Pei.
對了 裴司學
I learned two lines from a poem a couple of days ago.
我前兩天背了兩句詩
Would you please hear me recite them?
你要不要幫我聽一下
Of course.
好
In my life I know not what lovesickness is;
平生難解相思情
my body is like floating clouds and my heart is as still as duckweed.
身似浮影心如萍
When I was on Weimeng Mountain,
這段時間在威猛山
I missed you very much.
特別想念裴司學
Chen Qianqian, what are you talking about?
陳芊芊 你胡說什麼呀
You've had Han Shuo,
你明明都已經有韓爍了
yet you still try to seduce Minister Pei!
你還想著裴司學
The grass is always greener on the other side, huh?
你這是吃著碗裡的看著鍋裡的
As least I'm not as starving as you are!
那總比你餓著強
Will you mind your own business?
你能不能別一天天搗亂
Minister Pei is not interested in you at all!
裴司學根本就不理你
I know he isn't,
我知道他不搭理我
so I have to be forward!
我這不是上趕著嗎
When the pain of lovesickness comes;
證候來時遲坐起
the lamp is half-dusk while the moon is half-bright.
燈半昏時月半明
Qianqian, are these the rest two lines of your poem?
芊芊 你背的可是這兩句
Yes. Why did you complete it?
是 你怎麼還給接上了呢
Don't you remember?
你忘了
We recited it together when we were little.
這是你我兒時一起背的
Qianqian is ill-informed.
芊芊學識淺薄
She doesn't know that this poem isn't about the friendship
不懂這首詩的相思之意
between teacher and student, but expressing love.
表達的並非師生之情
Sorry if she offended you. Please forgive her.
多有唐突 司學莫怪
If she doesn't know, I can teach her.
芊芊不懂 我可以教她
But,
但是
I do think she knows what it means.
我怎麼覺得她是懂的
She does not know!
她不懂
She does!
她懂
-Do you know? -Do you know?
你懂嗎
Time's up! Class dismissed!
怎麼到時間了 下課了
Qianqian!
芊芊
Your Highness, what about your book?
少城主 那書不要了
My life is more important!
命重要
Tear down the east wall to repair the west wall,
拆東牆補西牆
which is not a permanent fix.
不過這也不是長久之計
I have to discuss it with the advisers.
我還是得找先生們去討論討論
In case I'll do something wrong
萬一一個不小心
to screw things up!
那不就走偏了
Yes!
對
Weimeng Mountain is located at the junction
威猛山地處玄虎城
of Xuanhu City and Huayuan City.
和花垣城交接之處
With its rough terrain,
山形險惡
it's been home to all kinds of bandits,
歷來匪患不絕
who were highly skilled in Kung Fu
山上集結了一批武功高強
and extremely fierce.
凶猛過人的山匪
The traveling merchants often got robbed
過往商隊 那是屢屢被劫
and suffered from their bullying.
真是苦不堪言
The bandit head, Meng Guo,
其匪首孟過
was as strong as a black bear,
黑熊般一身粗肉
had muscles all over his body,
疙裡疙瘩
and his skin was tough as an iron ox's.
鐵牛似遍體頑皮
He was invulnerable and he killed for pleasure.
刀槍不入 殺人如麻
People were all terrified of him as if he were devil!
窮凶惡煞一般讓人聞風喪膽
However, Her Highness
可是咱們少城主
was so resourceful and brave;
足智多謀 膽識過人
she had no fear of him at all!
絲毫不會怕他
She adopted "empty-city strategy",
當即唱出一出空城計
pretending that she didn't have enough force
假裝兵營空虛
and luring the bandits into the city.
誘使敵軍深入
Meng Guo was just a boor,
這孟過乃一介莽夫
who knew nothing about art of war.
哪懂什麼兵法
As expected, he fell into the trap
果然中計
and was captured by Young Master Han and the Second Princess.
被韓少君 二郡主一舉拿下
Great!
好
Take a guess.
你們猜猜看
What did Her Highness do to Meng Guo
少城主抓住孟過之後
after she caught him?
該如何處置他
Killed him! Killed him! Killed him!
殺了他 殺了他 殺了他
She released him!
放了
That's right! He was released!
沒錯 就是放了
In order to make Meng Guo willingly accept his defeat,
為了讓孟過心服口服 外帶佩服
Her Highness caught him seven times and released him seven times.
少城主將孟過是七擒七縱
As for the details,
哪七擒 哪七縱
please stay tuned.
等我慢慢說來
After the "empty-city strategy",
空城計後
Her Highness won a tough battle at Baiyin Valley, burned rattan-armor army,
又血戰白銀坑 火燒藤甲兵
outsmarted Meng Guo, debated with a bunch of scholars,
智激孟過 舌戰群儒
wisely borrowed Weimeng Mountain
巧借威猛山
and broke into the enemy's camp alone.
少城主孤身闖敵營
Amazing! So amazing!
好厲害 好厲害
In this way,
就這樣
Her Highness defeated bandit Meng Guo
少城主不動手指
with very little effort
就將凶猛山匪孟過收服
and enlisted him in the end.
納入麾下
Bravo! Bravo! Bravo!
好 好 好
Isn't this Her Highness?
這不是少城主嗎
Your Highness!
少城主
You were amazing defeating the bandits!
威猛山剿匪太厲害了
You were so amazing!
少城主威武
Of course, she only put in little effort.
少城主可不就動一根手指頭嗎
The bandits were caught by you and Young Master Han!
山匪都是您跟韓少君辛苦抓的
She was only in charge of releasing them.
她就只管放
Why should she take all the credit?
憑什麼功勞都讓她獨佔了去
Because she's the Crown Princess.
憑她是少城主
Your Highness, you are smart and brave!
少城主智勇雙全呀
Chuchu!
楚楚
Bad news! Your Highness!
不好了 三公主
What's up? Who did you frame again?
怎麼了 你又給誰挖坑了
Not me! It's Young Master Han.
不是小人 是韓少君
He's going to challenge Minister Pei!
韓少君要找裴司學的麻煩
Is it because of the...
是不是因為宗學
the poem I recited in class?
宗學堂的那首詩
Yes!
沒錯
Young Master Han thinks that Minister Pei likes you.
韓少君認定裴司學傾慕您
He learned that your engagement is still on,
聽說你們的婚約還沒解除
so he asked Minster Pei to the theater to have a duel!
便約他去戲院鬥個你死我活
My master is just a weak scholar.
我家公子一介柔弱書生
I'm afraid that...
我怕
It's my bad! It's my bad!
怪我 怪我
Pei Heng used to hate me so much.
以前裴恆這麼討厭我
He only sees me as a friend now.
現在頂多也就是把我當朋友
I can't put him in trouble!
我不能拖累他呀
What should I do?
這可怎麼辦
You asked me to be here,
韓少君將我約出來
yet you don't say anything.
卻又一句話也不說
The clan school is a place for study,
宗學堂乃清靜之地
where it's not proper to talk about affection.
不宜論男女之事
Minister Pei,
裴司學
why did you complete
剛才你同芊芊對詩
Qianqian's poem just now?
是為何意
Qianqian already has a husband.
芊芊畢竟是有夫之婦
I don't think
如此
your behavior was appropriate.
多有不妥吧
You are Qianqian's husband;
你是芊芊的夫君
you should've been the one she's closest to.
原本應該是她最親近的人
But you didn't cherish her well.
可你卻不好好珍惜
From now on,
從今以後
I won't hide my feelings for Qianqian anymore.
我會對芊芊表明心跡
I'll let her know who's good and who's bad,
讓她知道何為良人
so that she can leave you.
對你死心
Pei Heng,
裴恆
why don't you understand?
你為什麼就是不明白
You and Qianqian won't work.
你跟芊芊沒有可能
Maybe not right now
眼下芊芊被你迷惑
when she's blinded by you.
或許不可能
But in the future,
但未來很長
I will let Qianqian change her mind.
我會讓芊芊回心轉意的
Don't call her Qianqian as if you were close to her.
別一口一個芊芊的叫那麼親切
Qianqian!
芊芊
You...
你
Son of a bitch!
這個賤人
How dare you offend my wife?
竟敢覬覦我的妻子
You are shameless!
著實地不要臉
Minister Pei,
裴司學
I didn't mean that.
我並非這個意思
I...
我
People will get old.
紅顏易老
You will sooner or later lose your strength.
你總有人老珠黃的那一天哪
I didn't mean that either.
我也並非這個意思
Do you think your nonsense can fool me?
口出此言 騙得了哪個
Sounds like you've become smarter!
變聰明瞭嘛
I was fooling you!
我就是說來騙你的
You... You son of a bitch!
你你你 你這賤人
You are!
你是
No! You are!
你才是
Right now!
馬上
Never mind!
不必了
I've
我要說的
made myself very clear.
已經跟少君說得很明白了
I believe that you've heard me.
我相信少君也都聽明白了
I have one more question for you.
我最後問你一句
Do you know what kinda person
蘇子嬰的底細
Su Ziying really is?
你清不清楚
He is a threat to Qianqian and has been trying to harm her.
他對芊芊有異心 屢次害她
Are you aware of that?
這事你知不知道
Su Ziying is my hand-picked servant.
蘇子嬰是我一手栽培
If I knew nothing about him,
倘若不知道他的底細
how could I send him to Qianqian
我也不會把他送到芊芊身邊
to serve her?
替她料理家事
So, Young Master,
少君 你覺得
between you and Su Ziying,
我是信你
who do you think I'll trust?
還是信蘇子嬰
Seems like Pei Heng is really the one
看來蘇子嬰的所作所為
who asked Su Ziying to do all those things.
真的是裴恆指使的
Why don't you say I'm wise?
你為什麼不說少君英明
Young Master,
少君
there's no way that it's Minister Pei.
想想都不可能是裴司學
Minister Pei likes Her Highness.
裴司學喜歡少城主
He wouldn't ask Su Ziying to harm her repeatedly.
自然不會用蘇子嬰之手屢次害她
He might do that to you though.
害你還差不多
No...
不
You are quite smart when you are not expected to be.
你不該聰明的時候倒挺聰明
But it's not bad actually.
不過這樣也好
I'll find a chance
尋個機會
to get the goods on Su Ziying.
捏著蘇子嬰的短處
And I'll let Pei Heng know
讓裴恆看看
what kinda person
他把什麼樣的人
he sent to Qianqian.
送到了芊芊身邊
Let's see how ashamed he'll be then!
到時候我看裴恆如何自處
Who arranged today's play?
今天的戲誰安排的
It's such a coincidence!
真是太巧了
It's... It's such an accident!
太 太不巧了
Hurry, Zi Rui!
快點 梓銳
So slow!
磨磨嘰嘰
I'm here!
我來了
Where's Pei Heng?
裴恆呢
He left.
走了
What did you say to him?
你說什麼了
Nothing.
沒什麼
Han Shuo,
韓爍
I really overestimated you.
我可真是高看你了
For such a trivial thing,
就這麼大點事
you called Pei Heng here to set him up?
你還把裴恆叫出來搞鴻門宴啊
I just invited him over to have some tea.
我就是請他過來喝喝茶
Have some tea?
喝喝茶
You asked him to be here to watch these plays.
你約裴恆來看這種戲
Obviously, you were trying to insult
這不明擺著指桑罵槐地
and threaten him.
恐嚇別人嗎
It was just a love poem,
不就讀個情詩嗎
and I was the one who started it.
還是我先開口的
If you want to blame,
你要說有錯的話
you should blame me first.
也是我有錯在先啊
Would you stop making a scene?
你能不能不要這麼小題大做啊
You are a jealous man!
你這妒夫
Jealous man?
妒夫
Exactly! You are!
對 妒夫
You are indeed a jealous man!
你就是妒夫
You are so petty!
小家八子氣
Can't you open your mind just a little bit?
能不能大度點
I'm a jealous man?
我妒夫
You are my wife!
你是我妻子
You read a love poem
你當著我的面
with another man in front of me.
跟別的男人對情詩
I can't even ask about it?
我不能問問原因嗎
Why do you always side with Pei Heng
為什麼每次我跟裴恆起爭執
whenever I argue with him?
你都偏袒他
Don't you care about my feelings at all?
你就絲毫不在意我的心情嗎
Our marriage is over!
我與你夫妻緣盡
Just get out of here!
你趁早離開吧
Spare the room for me!
給我騰地方啊
Is that what you think?
難道你也是這麼想的
I...
我
What a crappy play is that?
這演的什麼亂七八糟的呀
I don't have time to explain!
我懶得跟你解釋
I'm leaving!
就這樣吧
Zi Rui!
梓銳
Where can I go to complain?
這苦衷對誰講
I feel sad, resentful, embarrassed and angry!
倒叫我又悲又恨又羞又惱
I'm filled with fury!
怒火滿腔
You asked me to be open-minded?
讓我大度是嗎
Okay, fine!
好 可以
Bai Ji.
白芨
Yes.
在
Deliver my invitation
去裴司學府上
to Minister Pei's mansion.
送我的請帖
I'll invite him to my place to have a talk!
邀他過府一敘
Why is Su Ziying here?
蘇子嬰怎麼在這兒
It must be Su Ziying who told Her Highness about this meeting.
一定是蘇子嬰跟少城主告的密
I saw him sneaking around
剛才我就看見
downstairs earlier,
他在下面鬼鬼祟祟
having a smug look on his face!
一副小人得志的樣子
What's this about?
少君這是
I want to apologize for what I did to Minister Pei.
自然是為了裴司學的事向你賠罪
Apologize?
賠罪
I know I was wrong.
我知錯了
I was being jealous.
是我善妒
In fact, you didn't do anything wrong.
其實 也不能說是你的錯
You just shouldn't have got angry with Pei Heng.
只是不應該遷怒人家裴恆
After all, I dragged...
畢竟是我拉
Forget it.
算了算了
Let's drink.
咱喝完這杯酒
It's water under the bridge.
過去的事就翻篇了
That's right!
翻篇了
Master! Young Master Han!
大當家的 韓少君
Mr. Meng, what are you doing here?
二當家的 你這是
Young Master invited me
韓少君說今晚月下飲酒
to have a drink tonight.
請在下赴約
Meng Guo just arrived in Huayuan City.
孟過他初到花垣城
He's alone
形單影隻
and has no company.
獨守空屋
So I invited him to join us for the meal.
所以請他共享良宵
Sure!
行
Yingying,
嬰嬰
what brought you here?
你這是
Young Master Han invited me
是韓少君說今晚要月下飲酒
to have a drink tonight.
叫小人務必赴約
But how could I eat together with Your Highness
小人如何能和三公主 韓少君
and Young Master Han?
平起平坐
I really don't dare.
小人愧不敢當
I knew Han Shuo wouldn't be this generous!
我就說韓爍不能這麼大度吧
Since you are here,
這來都來了
have some dinner with us.
那就照顧照顧大家
Besides, you can help us refill wine glasses and add dishes.
添個酒 加加菜什麼的
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦你了
In that case,
既然三公主這麼說
I'll listen to Your Highness.
那小人遵命了
It's just a meal.
吃個飯
Is it necessary to get the bodyguard and butler here?
沒必要還找保鏢跟管家吧
Minister Pei
還有裴司學
is on his way, too.
也在路上
You also invited Pei Heng?
裴恆你也請了
Han Shuo, what are you trying to do?
韓爍 你什麼意思啊
I've kept all the words
之前少城主所言
you told me in mind.
可字字刻在我心裡呀
I thought we've made a deal that it was all water under the bridge.
不是說好那事已經翻篇了嗎
Today I watched a play about a woman dumping her husband.
今日聽了一出女子休夫的戲
In the play, the couple loved each other
戲中夫妻二人本來相濡以沫
and got along very well at the first.
琴瑟和鳴
But another guy fell in love with the woman later,
就因為第三方對女方心生愛慕
which caused a big trouble to the family,
才搞得滿城皆知 家宅不寧
and the husband even got dumped in the end.
男子更是要被休夫
I did some thinking.
我認真反思過了
It's because the husband was too petty;
是這個做丈夫的沒有度量
he wasn't generous enough.
不肯容人
Huayuan City applauds for men's virtues.
花垣城崇尚夫德
So I'm going to abide by the local rule here.
我打算入鄉隨俗
I invited Meng Guo, Su Ziying and Pei Heng
於是我便將孟過 蘇子嬰 裴恆
here
約來
so that I can ask them
向各位請教
what they would do
如果是他們遇到了這樣的事情
if they were in the same situation?
該如何自處
That's unbelievable!
竟然有這樣的事
I can't stand this kinda thing...
我就看不慣這種
Shut your mouth!
給我閉嘴
No one thinks you are dumb.
你不說話沒人把你當啞巴
You scared me!
嚇我一大跳
Young Master Han, don't worry.
韓少君 您放心
I admit that I was up to no good
我曾經確實對我們大當家的
to Her Highness.
有過不軌之心
But how can I compare to her
但是我哪比得過裴司學這
childhood sweetheart Minister Pei,
青梅竹馬
or you, her newly-wed husband,
更比不過您這新婚燕爾
or even a "fine lady" like him.
更比不過這鶯鶯燕燕哪
Meng,
孟大哥
if you don't know idioms,
你要是不會說成語
stop using them.
還是別說了
But, Her Highness treats me
不過 大當家的平日對我
very well,
確實是照顧有加
if there's any misunderstanding,
有什麼誤會的
hope you'll forgive me.
各位 還請多多包涵
Now, let me toast to all of you!
我 敬大家一杯
Cheers!
幹了
What about you?
你呢
Although I once belonged to Minister Pei,
小人雖是裴司學的人
I've been sent to serve Her Highness,
但如今已被轉送於三公主
so I'll be loyal to Her Highness.
對三公主忠心不二
Whoever Her Highness chooses,
三公主屬意於誰
I'll go with her choice.
小人 就認定誰
You are playing fire, you know that?
你這是在玩火 你知道嗎
Minster Pei,
裴司學
what do you think
休夫一事
of the dumping husband thing?
你怎麼看
I think it's very good!
甚好
Minister Pei meant...
裴司學是說
Minister Pei meant that the wine was very good!
裴司學是說這酒 甚好
Very good?
甚好
Very good!
甚好啊
Your Highness,
少城主你
don't you have anything to say?
就沒什麼想說的
Do I have to?
我能不說嗎
What do you think?
你覺得呢
How can I
有什麼辦法能快進
fast-forward this plot?
趕緊跳過這段劇情
Han Shuo,
韓爍
I know your feelings
你對我的心意
for me.
我明白
But many things
只是很多事情這個
can't be explained.
道不清說不明的
You can't be too serious.
不能太走心
I need to protect my public image!
我這個人設不敢崩了
Right? Pei Heng.
你說是吧 裴恆
This thing
這個
is hard to explain.
事情道不清 說不明
We can't take it too seriously.
不能太當真
How about I...
我要不
Qianqian!
芊芊
Her Highness is drunk!
少城主喝醉了
No.
沒有
Then let's call it a day.
那今日咱們就暫且打住
We can discuss it some other time.
來日再辯個分明
Here!
來來來
Gentlemen, please continue to enjoy the meal.
諸位慢吃慢喝啊
Your Highness, let me take you to your room.
少城主 送你回房
Here, be careful.
來 慢點
I'm leaving, Han Shuo.
走了 韓爍啊
Master, take it easy!
大當家慢走
You are getting heavier!
越來越沉了
Stop it.
行了
You are not drunk?
沒喝醉呀
Drunk?
喝多
I've been practicing.
我現在練出來了
My capacity for wine is bigger than my courage now.
這酒量比膽要大
By the way, what's new with Su Ziying?
對了 最近蘇子嬰怎麼樣
This Yingying has been acting weirdly.
這個嬰嬰最近很奇怪
He tried to get into the study several times.
找機會來過書房幾次
But Bai Ji and I stopped him.
都被我和白芨給攔出去了
Then next time, just let him in.
那就找個由頭 讓他進去
I wanna see
我倒要看看
how he's going to harm me.
他要怎麼害我